让我们在这里做点乐事吧
Let's do something fun here.
我们会说 kubectl 比例 --副本=
We're gonna say kubectl scale --replicas=,
我们一起去 5 点保守点
let's go with 5 and
be conservative for the moment.
假设部署， /web。
Let's say deployment, /web.
好了如果我再看一次你可以看这里
Okay, now if I look at get all again,
you can look up here and
在我刚刚有一个网络容器运行之前，是吗 ?
see, before I just had one
web container running, right?
你可以看到这只在跑
You can see this one's just running.
但是这些，现在它还制造了五个版本的容器。
But these ones, now it's creating
five more versions of this container.
如果我再跑一次他们可能都跑了
And if I run this again,
they're probably all running now.
是的你可以看到他们都在跑
Yes, you can see that they're all running.
所以如果我回去刷新
So if I go back here and refresh,
任何时候我都不知道我要找的是哪个集装箱
any one of these times I don't know
actually which container I'm getting.
但我可能每次都有不同的容器
But I'm getting a different container
probably every single time.
所以现在我做了这个集群，我把它放大了。
So now I've taken this cluster and
I've scaled it up.
这就是我们在码头上出现问题的原因
So this is the thing that we had
a problem with docker compose,
它的前方没有负载平衡装置
that it didn't have a load
balancer in front of it.
Kubernetes 把它建在了它的基础上，所以它只为我们平衡所有这些东西。
Kubernetes has this built into it, so it's
just load balancing all this stuff for us.
所以根据你能做多少 RAM ，我们就说 25，
So depending on how much RAM you can do,
let's just say 25,
如果你没有太多的 RAM ，请不要这样做。
if you don't have very much RAM,
don't do this.
我的电脑大概会说你为什么要这样对我
My computer's probably gonna say,
why are you doing this to me?
你现在可以看到，我有 25 个版本的容器在我的电脑上运行。
You can see now, I have 25 versions of
that container running on my computer.
看，我们可以看温度，就在我的电脑上，
Just watch, we can watch the temperature,
right there on my computer,
一切都会好起来的
and it's just gonna go up.
现在他们大部分都在跑
And now, most of them are running.
但是，我们是如何感受这一点的，很酷的吧 ?
But, how do we feel about that,
pretty cool right?
我要见头布莱恩
I need to see heads, yes Brian.
这太酷了你给我留下了深刻的印象我只是开玩笑
This is very cool,
you're very impressed, I'm just kidding.
再看一次我们会看到
And one more time, we'll see that,
需要 25 个， 25 个当前正在运行， 25 个已就绪。
25 are desired, 25 are currently running,
and 25 are ready.
你可以看到所有这些都在运行。
And you can see all of
these are now running.
一旦我完成了这些不同的事
And then as soon as I'm done
running all these different things,
我只能说一，一，它就会把它放大缩小。
I can just say replicas, 1, and
it's just going to scale that back down.
我们会在这里看到它会说
And we'll see here that it'll say,
Kubectl 来了结束了
Kubectl come on, terminating.
它为我们终止了所有这些不同的东西。
It's terminating all these
different things for us.
现在我们可以做各种有趣的事情了
Now we could do all sorts of fun stuff.
我们可以对其中一个进行健康检查，然后进行容器崩溃，并且
We could put like a health check on one of
these and then make a container crash, and
那么它会为我们重新启动容器。
then it would restart the containers for
us.
它会为我们做些很酷的事情
It'll do a bunch of really cool stuff for
us.
它执行所有监视，重新启动和重新运行所有这些内容的操作
It does all that monitoring and restarting
and rerunning all this stuff for
你从盒子里出来
you out of the box.
好吧一旦我们完成了这一切
Okay, and then as soon as we
are done with all of this,
你只能说 kubectl 删除全部
you can just say kubectl delete all --all.
好了好了
There you go.
一切都被擦掉了你又回到了一个空的石板上
Everything just gets wiped off and
you are back to a blank slate again.
好吧最后一件事
Okay, last thing here.
如果让我们说，其实我是非常认真的，因为这是一个库伯内特项目
If let's say, actually, I was very serious
about this being a Kubernetes project
我也不会用作曲的方式来完成这一工作
going forward, I would not run
this with compose in production.
这不是我建议的方式
That's just not the way that
I would suggest doing it.
我想说的是 kompose 转换。
I would say kompose convert.
现在你可以在这里看到，我有 web-deployment.yaml， web-service.yaml.
And then now you can see here, I have
web-deployment.yaml, web-service.yaml.
它为我生成所有 Kubernetes 文件。
It generates all of
the Kubernetes files for me.
因此，我将开始使用 Docker 编写，因为我不记得所有语法
So I will get started with docker compose
because I don't remember all of the syntax
就在我头上
off the top of my head.
我不想这样
I don't want to.
所以我先和博士一起作曲然后说 kompose convert ，然后我就
So I'll do with docker compose first, and
then I'll say kompose convert, and then I
突然间， Kubernetes 配置了我各种不同的服务。
suddenly have Kubernetes configurations
for all my various different services.
所以这是一个从大门开始的好方法
So it's a good way to get
kinda started out of the gate.
所以库伯内特是非常强大的。
So Kubernetes is extremely powerful.
我刚给你看了几个 Kubernetes 的 Hello World
I just showed you basically
the Hello World of Kubernetes.
还有 900 万的东西，对吧 ?
It does 9 million more things, right?
这就是谷歌的基础设施，很多基础设施。
This is what runs Google's infrastructure,
much of that infrastructure.
Azure现在在库伯内特斯跑了
Azure's now run on Kubernetes.
这行业的方向正朝着库伯内特的方向发展
It's kind of, the direction of the
industry is heading towards Kubernetes in
几乎每一种意义上的意义
almost every sense of the word.
所以我想说知道它是什么，它是怎么运作的，为什么
So I'm gonna say that it's useful to
know what it is, how it works, why
你会用它，除非你必须要用它，否则就不一定要用它。
you would use it, and then not necessarily
use it unless you absolutely have to.
库兹我要告诉你库伯内特解决了很多问题
Cuz I'm gonna tell you that Kubernetes
solves a lot of problems but
它会在你运行库伯内特时产生自己独特的问题
it creates its own unique set of
problems when you're running Kubernetes.
就像我在开始之前说的
Like I said before at
the beginning of this,
它是一个复杂的产品解决了复杂的问题
it's a complicated product that
solves complicated problems.
所以如果你没有复杂的问题，不要给自己一个复杂的问题。
So if you don't have complicated problems,
don't give yourself a complicated problem.
我在这件事上的立场是一样的。
Is kind of my stance on the matter.
好酷，我在这里展示的，我不会教你怎么做
Now, what's really cool, what I've shown
here and I'm not gonna show you how to do
就像一点点的利益冲突一样。
it, do the kind of like conflict
of interest a little bit is.
我一直在给你展示如何用 kubectl 或 kube 的控制来做事情。
I've been showing you how to do
things with kubectl or kube control.
如果我想去 Azure Kubernetes 服务
If I wanted to go to
Azure Kubernetes service,
我就像从 Docker 桌面切换到 Minikubbe一样，改变我的环境。
I would just change my context just like
I switch from docker desktop to Minikube.
我要把它转至 Azure 作为我的背景。
I would just switch that
to Azure as my context.
突然我控制了我整个 Azure 的部署
And all sudden I'd be controlling my
entire Azure deployment of Kubernetes.
所以我所做的一切都在我的电脑上
So everything that I was just
running locally on my computer,
本产品在生产过程中以同样的方式工作 100% 。
it works 100% the same way in production.
所以如果我说了
So if I just said,
将此扩展至 25 ，它将转至云，并将其扩展至 25。
scale this to 25, it would go out to
the cloud and scale that out to 25.
我不打算展示的另一个原因是 Kubernetes 不便宜
The other reason I'm not gonna
show is Kubernetes is not cheap.
所以如果我们这样做了
[LAUGH] So if we did that and
我在给你展示如何在我们的车间里
I was showing you how to
do that in our workshop,
你可能会在账单上跑出 10 块或 20 块之类的对吧
you'd probably run up $10 or $20 with
the bill or something like that, right?
这不便宜
It's not cheap.
所以我把一堆链接留在了
So I left a bunch of
links down in the course
这些文件是从 AKS开始的
documents here of getting started on AKS,
EKS 开始， GKE开始。
getting started on EKS, and
getting started on GKE.
我是 AKS 的一部分我觉得这是个好产品
I am partial to AKS,
I think it's a good product.
也许试试那个我不知道
So maybe try that one, I don't know.